hi I'm Brett curus and in this video I'm
going to show you how to do an rkc plank
I learned the rkc plank from my friend
Pavo sataline he's the the creator of
the Russian kabell club and uh and this
is an evolving exercise it's it's it's
uh morphed into something um even more
effective even over the last couple
years he keeps improving upon it so this
is the current way that he's doing it
and uh I want to mention up front that
the the world record right now for a
standard plank is like an hour and 20
minutes so it it's that's you know that
just shows that the plank is pretty
lowlevel activity um for for some people
at least I can only do it for a couple
minutes but um this way um the RCC plank
is is a way to make a plank really like
you just give it your all for for like
10 seconds and go all out and you can
actually make it really really
challenging to the point where you're
just exerting yourself as hard as
possible for 10 seconds and then you
rest when I do the rkc plank um I start
I actually start trembling um but I'm
gonna have my friend Kelly Davis here
show you how to do it so she's going to
get into a standard plank
position this is just a standard plank
she's got some some anter pelvic tilt so
it looks like she's extended but she's
not okay so head is in good alignment
she's not you know she's not looking up
she's she's in neutral your elbows are
going to be directly under the armpits K
she's going to make really tight fists
for IR radiation all right now she's
gonna kind of screw her shoulders into
place via like an external rotation
moment okay shoulders are screwed into
place all right now she's going to
squeeze the legs together adducting them
she's going to forcefully contract the
quadriceps to pull her kneecaps up she's
going to squeeze her glutes as hard as
possible now here's the kicker when you
squeeze your glutes that makes it way
harder for the abdominals and the
obliques but now this is what makes it
super hard hit a neutral to the chin
good right there okay here's what makes
it super hard now she's going to pull
her elbows towards her toes and her toes
to her elbows as hard as she can like
she's trying to Pike up in a pike
position but she keeps her glutes
contracted so you see she's starting to
tremble all right so you know I'll
however do this for like 10 seconds and
just go give it your all and then stops
you can you can stop now so as you can
see this is a lot more challenging than
a standard Plank and she's breathing
pretty hard um you know if she just did
a normal plank she could she could do
that for a couple minutes but this way
it made it a lot more challenge so give
it a try I'm sure you'll like it